Guide to the Robert Roth papers, 1973-1990
Roth, Robert papers, 1973-1990
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Robert Roth papers, 1973-1990
7325
Robert Roth, 1950-1990
14 cubic ft.
Correspondence, periodicals, publications, subject files, catalogs, legal files.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
The Robert Roth papers include correspondence, periodicals, publications, subject files, an AIDS file, and an international file pertaining chiefly to the international gay rights movement of the 1970s through the 1980s; also, pornography and erotica catalogs and material, and legal files pertaining to Roth's work as an attorney in landlord-tenant cases.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Robert Roth was born in Englewood, New Jersey in 1950. He graduated from the Horace Mann School in 1967, Cornell University in 1971, and the Fordham Law School in 1975. While at Cornell, he was one of the co-founders of the Student Homophile League (later the Gay Liberation Front), which at the time was only the second gay rights organization among U.S. universities. As a lawyer, he specialized in landlord-tenant cases, winning the landmark Chin vs. London Management case in 1982, which ruled that unmarried tenants shared survivors' rights to an apartment. Another courtroom victory established First Amendment rights for the Swedish gay magazine "Revolt," which had been seized by U.S. Customs. In New York City, where he lived, Roth was involved with several legal and human rights organizations, particularly the Bar Association for Human Rights of Greater New York.
a principal project of Robert Roth was the compilation and cataloguing of international gay publications, and the accumulation of information and documents pertaining to the international gay rights movement. In addition to collecting numerous periodicals from many countries and all parts of the world, he corresponded with gay people in developing countries where there was no gay freedom movement, providing contacts and materials to those who might otherwise have had little awareness of or access to the international gay liberation movement. He used his several travels abroad to collect further printed material and publications to broaden his international collection. Many of the publications are very rare, and provide insight into the emerging issues of gay rights throughout the world in the 1970s and 1980s. One component of his international collection is lists and bibliographies of international gay organizations, and publications. He also corresponded with several leaders in the movement, especially John D. Stamford of "Spartacus," John Hubert and "Paz y Liberacion," and Claude Courouve of "Aleph."
Roth privately published a newsletter (1977-1979), which discussed the international gay rights movement, and was instrumental in promoting and distributing other publications concerned with the issue, particularly "Paz y Liberacion." Under the pseudonym "Calaph Timmerman," Roth published in 1988 an article "Home Remedies for the Holocaust - A Few Simple Techniques for Staying Alive," which was widely distributed. another major undertaking was a microform project with the National Gay Archives and Library, for which he composed an extensive bibliography of gay periodicals and publications.
Roth died of AIDS related causes and Hodgkins Disease in July of 1990. Prior to his death he had been in contact with Brenda J. Marston of the Human Sexuality Collection, and had made arrangements for the gift of his personal papers and international collection.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
The Collection has been divided into six series, which basically reflect the organizational pattern employed by Roth, in which the primary level of access in the folder title. His original folder headings have been in all cases retained. A short personal group (Series I) includes a small amount of personal correspondence, his "Calaph Timmerman" correspondence, and his initial dealings with the Cornell University Department of Manuscripts and Archives Human Sexuality Collection. Series II consists of Roth's subject files, which include files on individuals, corporations, service organizations, gay and human rights organizations, articles from magazines and newspapers, and material on the Fordham Law School alumni group, and the Cornell University Gay and Lesbian Alumni Association, and many other topics. These are presently organized as he kept them, non-alphabetically. As with the International files (Series III) groupings were made conceptually, or according to his personal understanding of the material. In addition to the many periodicals and publications, Series III includes correspondence with and letters from people around the world. Series IV consists of a legal file, concerned chiefly with landlord-tenant cases. Roth kept a separate AIDS file (Series V), of health publications and scientific findings. Series VI is a diverse collection of miscellaneous writings and printed material, which were perhaps intended to be interfiled in other parts of his collection.
In addition to the publications and correspondence, the collection includes two videos, erotic and pornographic material and catalogs which are distributed in different series, legal briefs and publications, photographs, and a selection of perfunctory solicitation mailings dealing mainly with gay and human rights organizations.
An index to the periodicals follows the box and folder listings, but does not always include the substantial number of titles within specific nation folders in Series III. The "France" and "Japan" folders particularly contain many publications.
Some American publications were removed from the collection and distributed into other parts of the Human Sexuality Collection. A list of these is available, as is a bibliography Roth compiled for the National Gay Archives and Library Microform Project, though it is not to be inferred that all these titles remained in the collection when it was acquired by the Human Sexuality Collection.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Roth, Robert, 1950-1990.
Subjects:
Homosexuality.; Gay men.; Lesbians.; Gay liberation movement.; AIDS (Disease)--Prevention.; Homosexuality--Law and legislation.; Sex and law.; Landlord and tenant--Cases.
Places:
Europe--Periodicals.; Asia--Periodicals.; Africa--Periodicals.; South America--Periodicals.; Europe--Social life and customs.; Asia--Social life and customs.; Africa--Social life and customs.; South America--Social life and customs.
Form and Genre Terms:
Pornography.; Erotica.
Occupations:
Lawyers.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Available Copies:
"Use copy" of videocassette available.
RELATED MATERIAL
Related collections include the Cornell University Gay Liberation Records (Student Homophile League), #37-6-1589, and the Mariposa Foundation Collection, #7300, to which Roth had previously donated international material.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Personal Files
Box 1 folders 1-9
Series II. Subject Files
Box 1 folder 10 through Box 4 folder 17
Series III. International Files
Box 4 folder 18 through Box 9 folder 41, Box 10, and Box 15
Series IV. Legal Files
Box 11 folder 1 through Box 12 folder 29
Series V. AIDS File
Box 13 folders 1-35
Series VI. Printed Miscellany
Box 14 folders 1-40
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Robert Roth Personal Files
  - 'Calaph Timmerman' Correspondence pertaining to Robert Roth's article "A Few Simple Techniques for Staying Alive - Home Remedies for the Holocaust" (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Cornell University Correspondence Collection on Human Sexuality (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "This book is dedicated to Antonio Paulo Coutinho Machado, a truly extraordinary man..." (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Perfunctory Correspondence: solicitation for funds from various human and sexual rights organizations; brochures for erotica and pornography (Box 1, Folder 4-9)
  - Robert Roth, James Kelly interview, 9/9/89, V-107; USE COPY = V-133
- Series II. Subject Files
  - Paz y Liberacion (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Paz y Liberacion Correspondence with John Hubert (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Ham Radio (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Facilities (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Guardian Angels (NYC) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cruising Areas (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Buttons (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Gay Guides List (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - New York Area Lists (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
  - Newsletter originals. [The Newsletter was a publication edited and privately produced by Robert Roth, pertaining chiefly to the international gay rights movement.] (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Gay Lawyers Lists (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "Certificate of Change - Cornell University Gay and Lesbian Alumni Association, Inc." (CUGALA) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Times Square Studios (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Stephen F. Temmer (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Venereal Disease Clinics (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Gay Laws (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
  - Allen Young (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Gay Community Service Center (NYC) (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Gay Liberation Community Center (Box 1, Folder 32-33)
  - Christopher Street Liberation Day Committee (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Bar Association for Human Rights (Box 1, Folder 35-37)
  - New York Law Group (Box 1, Folder 38-40)
  - Sexual Law Reporter (Box 1, Folder 41-44)
  - Cornell University Gay and Lesbian Alumni Association (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Cornell University Gay and Lesbian Alumni Association Calendars (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Christopher Street Financial, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - FAIRPAC (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Fraternity (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Fund for Human Dignity, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Gay and Lesbian Adolescent Social Services, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund, Inc. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Gay Pride Day 1983, Video 108
  - Donahue, AIDS 7/15/83, Video 109
  - Gaysweek Index (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Library Microfilm Project (Box 2, Folder 2-7)
  - Fordham Registration Materials (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - JRM Manufacturing (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Boyeros (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Filmco (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Fordham Newspapers (Box 2, Folder 12-15)
  - Surgeon General - Understanding AIDS (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Campaign (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Project Inform (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Avalon Video News (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - New York State Tenant and Neighborhood Coalition (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Night of a Thousand Gowns (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Out/Look (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Parents FLAG: Parents and Friends of Lesbians and Gays (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - PWA Coalition (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Project Inform (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Pride Guide (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Joe Rosa (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - SAGE - Senior Action in a Gay Environment (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Duck (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Ken Sherrill - Politics (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Stonewall Democratic Club (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Thor E. Wood (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - New York State Tenant and Neighborhood Coalition (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - European Trip (Box 2, Folder 34-35)
  - Broad Street Journal and BSG Advertisements (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Seibu Productions (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Charlie's West (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Outcome - Man-Age Press (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center (NYC) The Center Voice (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Lesbian Mothers' National Defense Fund (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Lesbian Rights Project (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center (NYC) Center Stage (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center (NYC) Center Happenings (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Lesbian and Gay Community Services Center (NYC) Center Sports (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Lesbian and Gay Community Center (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Maxrich Inc. (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - GHMC (Gay Men's Health Crisis) - Legal Services (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Gay Psychological Counselling Groups (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Gay Rights National Lobby (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Gay Switchboard (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Gaytek (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - God's Love We Deliver (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Act Up (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - AIDS Action Council (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - AIDS Awareness Networking Project at New York University (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - AIDS Institute (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - American Foundation for AIDS Research - AMFAR (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - AIDS Research Center - Bailey House (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Bar Association for Human Rights of Greater New York (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Bar Association for Human Rights of Greater New York - Pro-Bono Committee (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Lambda Legal Defense and Education Fund Lambda Update (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Lambda Financial Advisor (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Gay and Lesbian Advocates and Defenders - GLAD (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Gay and Lesbian Community Service of New York, Inc. - GLCS (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Gay and Lesbian Switchboard of New York (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Gay Men's Health Crisis (GMHC) (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - GMHC News Updates (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - GMHC - The Volunteer (Box 2, Folder 70-71)
  - Hadassah (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Harrison, Kooden and Associates (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Health Education AIDS Liaison (HEAL) (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Heritage of Pride, Inc. (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Human Rights Campaign Fund (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Institute for Human Identity (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Ithaca (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Mariposa (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Metropolitan Community Church of New York (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Mayor Dinkins (NYC) (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Names Project (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - National Association of Lesbian and Gay Alcoholism Professionals (NALGAP) (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - National Gay and Lesbian Task Force (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - National Gay Rights Advocates (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - National Gay Task Force (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - New Jersey Act Up - "Outcry" (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - NYC Gay and Lesbian Anti-Violence Project (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - NYC Gay Men's Chorus (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - NYC Gay Men's Chorus - Chorus Lines (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Amalgamated American Male (AAM) - Footman (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - AAM - Handyman (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - AAM - American Greek Alliances (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - AAM - Rainmaker (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - AAM - RFA (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - AAM - Undercoverman (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Bibliographies, Book Lists (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Lists (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Directories, Lists, Guides (Box 3, Folder 3-6)
  - Advocate (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Amnesty International (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bars, Advertisements, etc. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Books, Correspondence Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - California (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - COHLA: Comite Homosexual Latino Americano (Box 3, Folder 12-13)
  - Colorado (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Connexions - An International Women's Quarterly (Box 3, Folder 15-17)
  - Esperanto (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Arthur Evans (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Gay Activists Alliance - Constitution (Box 3, Folder 20-22)
  - Gay American Historical Society (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Gay Asian Association (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Gay Insurgent - A Gay Left Journal (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Gay Roommate Service (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - International Gay News Agency (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Linguistic Articles (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Miami (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - National Coalition of Black Gays (Box 3, Folder 30-31)
  - New York Coalition of Black/Third World Gays (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Nueva York (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Tom Parker (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Ramona Fan Club (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Sister Cities (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Third World Gays (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - VILLAGE - Village Improvement through a Local Lesbian and Gay Effort (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - We Are Everywhere, International (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - World Congress of Sexology (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Lists - Current Changes (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Lists - Current Working Copies (Box 3, Folder 42-47)
  - Mailing Lists (Box 3, Folder 48)
  - Newsletter (Robert Roth) (Box 3, Folder 49-51)
  - To Be Answered - International Letters (Box 3, Folder 52)
  - To Be Answered - Domestic Letters (Box 3, Folder 53)
  - To Be Filed - Leaflets and Miscellaneous (Box 3, Folder 54)
  - To Be Read - Magazines (Box 3, Folder 55)
  - New York Community of Lesbian and Gay Organizations (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Black and White Men Together, New York (Box 4, Folder 2-4)
  - Greater Gotham Business Council - Greater Gotham Business Council Newsletter (Box 4, Folder 5-10)
  - Groves Conference (Box 4, Folder 11-12)
  - Books Sent (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Bars, Discos (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Alexander (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Swingers Magazines (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Sovereign Advertising - Tomcat Books (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Series III. International Files
  - Third World List (Box 4, Folder 18-19)
  - The International List of Gay Organizations and Publications (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Publication Lists (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Spanish (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Address Lists (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - International Gay Association - New York Chapter (Box 4, Folder 24-25)
  - International Gay Association - Washington Latitudes - Journal of the International Lesbian and Gay Association (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - International Gay Association - Fourth Meeting, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - International Gay Association - International Gay Association News (Box 4, Folder 28-38)
  - Sierra Domino - Sierra Domino Newsletter (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Marty Levine (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Pen Pal Clubs (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - To Be Sent - Xerox Press Releases (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Miscellaneous Press Releases, Lists, Publications (Box 4, Folder 43-45)
  - Brasil (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Asians and Friends - New York (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - OG - Oriental Guys (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Bizar 2 - International S/M Quarterly (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Viking and Scandinavian Publications (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Homosexuality in Canada (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - All Lavender - International Gay Guide (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Reporter - Den Oberoende Gaytidningen I Norden (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Rites - Toronto, Ontario, Canada (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Revolt - Mot Sexuella Fördomar (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Sweden (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Front D'alliberament Gai de Catalunya (FAGC) (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Surinam (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Puerto Rico (Box 5, Folder 14-15)
  - Portugal (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Polynesia (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Desert Patrol (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Espana (Box 5, Folder 19-23)
  - South America (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Stephan Likosky (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Spartacus Guide (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Mexico (Marc) (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Mexico Trip (Box 5, Folder 28-32)
  - Netherlands (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Spartacus - Corrections (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Rome (Ancient) (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Pacific, Australia, New Zealand (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Spain and Portugal (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Europe - South (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Europe - North (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Japan (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Eastern Europe (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - New York City News (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Renaissance Africa (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Emilia Saito Bearse (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - South Africa (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Singapore (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Poland (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Philippines (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Peru (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Panama (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Thailand (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Trinidad and Tobago (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Uruguay (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Yugoslavia (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - Venezuela (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Revolt - Sweden (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - Letters (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Dominican Republic (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Colombia (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Lebanon - Middle East (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Japan - Books and Magazines (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Barazoku (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Japan (Box 6, Folder 6-8)
  - Jamaica (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Ireland (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Indonesia (Box 6, Folder 11-12)
  - India, Pakistan, Ceylon (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - India (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
  - Argentina (Box 6, Folder 16-17)
  - Africa (Box 6, Folder 18-19)
  - Argentina - Political (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Asia (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Australia (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Aleph - Centre d'Information sur l'Homosexualité Claude Courouve (Box 6, Folder 23-28)
  - Germany (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Greece (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Guatemala (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Iceland (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Body Politic - Gay Liberation Journal (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Glad Day Books (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Caribbean - West Indies (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Chile (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - China (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Brazil - 1982 Trip (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Brazil - Marcos (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Brazil - João Antãnio de Souza Mascarenhas (Box 6, Folder 40-43)
  - Brazil Travel Club (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Brazil (Box 6, Folder 45-47)
  - Bermuda (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Austria (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Spartacus Guide John D. Stamford Correspondence (Box 6, Folder 50-58)
  - Mexico - FHAR (Frente Homosexual de Accion Revolucionaria) (Box 6, Folder 59-60)
  - Mauritius (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Malta (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Malaysia - Jaivan Ho (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Malaysia (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Arabia - Arabic Language (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Argentina - Somos (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Argentina - Somos (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Belgium (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Pleiguei - O Jornal do Homo (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Lampião - Rio de Janeiro (Box 7, Folder 6-8)
  - Entender; Jornal do Gay (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Brazil - Publications (Box 7, Folder 10-13)
  - Canada, Quebec, Prairie (Box 7, Folder 14-18)
  - Hong Kong (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Ellos; Hombres (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - El Otro (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Costa Rica (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Cuba (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Denmark (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Pan (Box 7, Folder 25-26)
  - Edinburgh (Box 7, Folder 27-28)
  - Finland (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - France (Box 7, Folder 30-36)
  - Greece (Box 8, Folder 1-2)
  - Lambda (Box 8, Folder 3-7)
  - OMPO (Box 8, Folder 8-12)
  - Jamaica Gaily News (Box 8, Folder 13-15)
  - India, Pakistan (Box 8, Folder 16-17)
  - Israel (Box 8, Folder 18-19)
  - Gay Jewish Organizations (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Fuori! (Box 8, Folder 21-29)
  - Japan Trip, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Japanese Publications (Box 8, Folder 31-37)
  - Nuestro Cuerpo (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Nuevo Ambiente (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Politica Sexual (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Panorama (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - L'Europeo article "Rapporto Omosessual" (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - AIRDO - Les Durham (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Fuori! (Box 9, Folder 2-6)
  - Spanish Bibliography (Box 9, Folder 7-8)
  - Sek (Box 9, Folder 9-10)
  - Pan (Box 9, Folder 11-12)
  - Spartacus (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Amsterdam Gay Press (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Dutch Society for the Integration of Homosexuality COC - COC International Newsletter (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - New Zealand Gay News (Box 9, Folder 16-18)
  - Out! (Box 9, Folder 19-20)
  - National Gay Rights Coalition (New Zealand) (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - DNF 48 (Norway) (Box 9, Folder 22-23)
  - Pafuera! (Box 9, Folder 24-25)
  - Aghois (Box 9, Folder 26-28)
  - Lambda - Barcelona (Box 9, Folder 29-32)
  - Swiss Gay (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Thailand (Box 9, Folder 34-35)
  - Afuera (Box 9, Folder 36)
  - International Correspondence (Box 9, Folder 37-41)
  - Schwuchtel 1975-1978 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Germany 1975-1978 (Box 15, Folder 2-3)
  - United Kingdom, England 1973-1975 (Box 15, Folder 4-5)
  - HIM, Germany 1975 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Gay News England 1975-1979 (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
  - Gaia's Guide England 1975-1979 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Wales 1978 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Scotland n.d. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Gay News Germany 1977-1979 (Box 15, Folder 12-17)
  - Volumes
    - Gaia's Guide, 1978, 1979 (Box 10)
    - Italia Gay, 1984 (Box 10)
    - Gai Pied Lesbia Guide, 1984 (Box 10)
    - Revolt (Box 10)
    - Le Guide Gai du Québec (Box 10)
    - Les Homosexuels s'Organisent (Box 10)